# Miguel A. Perez-Xochicale

I am a hard working and enthusiastic person. Principles of responsability, human kidness and honesty guide me through my life decisions.

# Research Goals

Currently as a doctoral researcher, I am gaining a deeper understanding of Nonlinear Dynamics to create novel analysis and interpretation of motion capture systems. I am deeply insterested in the field of Human Activity Recognition and Human-Robot Interaction.

# **Education**

#### PhD in Electronic, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Birmingham, UK

University of Birmingham,

Nov. 2014 – Present

Thesis: Automatic Non-linear Nonlinear Dynamics Approach to Human Activity Recognition

Advisors: Chris Baber and Neil Cooke

Master Degree in Electronics

Puebla, Mexico

National Institute of Astrophysics, Optics and Electronics,

Sep. 2004 - Sep. 2006

Thesis: Digital Filter FIR with less multipliers 🚨

Advisor: Gordana Jovanovic Dolecek Professional license: 6294064

Bachelor degree in Electronic Engineering

Puebla, Mexico

Technological Institute of Puebla, Aug. 1999 – Sep. 2004

Thesis: Speed control of a two degrees of freedom Robot 🚨

Professional license: 4907567

# **Experience**

#### Professional

### Instituto Nacional de Astrofísica, Óptica y Electrónica

Tonantzintla, Mexico

Resaerch Assistant at the Robotics Laboratory

February 2013 – August 2013

A Human-Robot Interaction Demo Dance

Detailed achievements:

**Madero University** 

Puebla, Mexico

Resaerch Assistant at the Robotics Laboratory

January 2012 - January 2013

Mechatronic Laboratory Proposal

Detailed achievements:

• A Design of a Mechatronic Laboratory was elaborated as a proposal project for the Mechatronic engineering career at Madero University in order to offer adequate facilities to students, professors and researchers •

#### Instituto Nacional de Astrofísica, Óptica y Electrónica

Tonantzintla, Mexico August 2003 - March 2004

Profesional Resident: 6 month full time in a research institution

Speed control of a two degrees of freedom Robot

Detailed achievements:

- o Programming a Microcontroller PIC 16F84 and 16F877
- o Programming Virtual Instruments with LabVIEW
- Serial Communication RS-232

#### Teaching.....

Puebla. Mexico

**TECMilenio University** Hight School Teacher

Euclidian Geometry 3, Information Technology 3 and Microsoft Office Access 3

Puebla, Mexico

Madero University

Research Assistant Professor in Mechatronic Engineering

Spring 2012 - Autumn 2012

August 2013-December 2013

Fundamentals of Automation Q, Industrial Electronics Q, Research Projects II Q, Metrology Q, Physics Q. Computer Integrating Manufacturing, and Power Electronics

University Iberoamericana Puebla

Puebla, Mexico

Research Assistant Professor in Electronic Engineering

Spring 2007 - Spring 2012

Stochastic Processes Course 3, Digital Signal Processing 3, Noise and Stochastic Processes and Analog Filters

**Technological Institute Superior of Atlixco** 

Atlixco, Mexico

August 2006 - June 2007 Research Assistant Professor in Mechatronic and Electric Engineering Electronic I, Numerical Methods, and Electricity and Magnetism. (January-June 2007.) Electricity and Magnetism, and Electricity and Industrial Electronics ( August-December 2006)

## **Awards and Honours**

- o I was selected to be part of MECATE 2015, an international public entrepreneurship program. My project of a low-cost educational robot was selected from 125 applications received from 35 countries.
- o Full PhD Degree Scholarship in the UK from November 2014 to November 2017 from the Mexican National Council on Science and Technology
- First place at the 2013 Mexican Tournament of Robotics in the cathegory at HOME.
- o Full Master Degree Scholarship in Mexico from 2004-2006 from the Mexican National Council on Science and Technology

# Languages

Spanish: Native tongue

English: IETLS Band Score 6.0: Listening 6.0, Reading 7.0, Writing 6.0, Speaking 5.5.

11/01/14

# Computer skills

Operative Systems: Windows, GNU-Linux Ubuntu and Debian

Programing and markup languages: GNU-Octave, GNU-emacs, MATLAB, C++, Kdevelop, Code Composer Studio, ng-spice, LabVIEW, Arduino, Processing, LATEX, and beginner at Robot Operating System (ROS)

# **Extracurricular Activities**

- o On June 2013, I founded LibrE Robotics, a non-profit organization for learning and sharing knowledge to build conditions for a better world.
- o Giving advice on student projects such as Haptic Referee Glove Lightmetre and Pychometre using Arduino, Smart Irrigation, Persistent Of Vision Bicycle Wheel, a Delta Robot Structure 3

o Item 3. This item is particularly long and therefore normally spans over several lines. Did you notice the indentation when the line wraps?

## **Publications**

G. Jovanovic-Dolecek and Miguel A. Perez-Xochicale. *One Method for Design of Wideband FIR Filters Without Multipliers*. Puebla, Mexico, February 2006. Proc. of the 16th IEEE Conference on Electronics, Communications and Computers, CONIELECOMP 2006, published by IEEE Computer Society, No. 0-7695-2505-9/06. 2006 IEEE 2.

Miguel A. Perez-Xochicale and G. Jovanovic-Dolecek. *A New Method for Design Narrow Band Lowpass FIR Filters Using a Scale Function*. Veracruz, Mexico, November 2006. 2nd International Conference on Electronic Design, Proc. edited by Victor Champac at all, ISBN 968-9085-01-8, pp.85-89, [2].

Miguel A. Perez-Xochicale and G. Jovanovic-Dolecek. *A New Method for Design Narrow Band Lowpass FIR Filters Using a Scale Function*. Chihuahua, Mexico, August 2006. 28th International Congress of Electronic Engineering, Proc edited by ITCH Chiuahua, 2006, pp.165-168, 

D.